<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-06-17T15:42:19-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Revisiting Hogwarts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/08/12/Revisiting-Hogwarts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Revisiting Hogwarts" /><published>2016-08-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-08-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/08/12/Revisiting-Hogwarts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/08/12/Revisiting-Hogwarts.html">&lt;p&gt;You can never go home again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept thinking about this idea as I read &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter and the Cursed Child.&lt;/em&gt; When I read the script last weekend, I wanted to go back to Hogwarts again. It turns out that’s hard to do, even for the creator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a work that is to my mind clearly &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the “eighth Harry Potter Book,” this might be a harsh way to judge it. So let’s consider this post a &lt;em&gt;reaction&lt;/em&gt;, rather than a review. I’ll have more to say later, but these are my first thoughts, unaffected by the opinions of other Potter fans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first thought is that honestly, this is a work doesn’t need to exist.  Don’t get me wrong, I had fun reading it. It was nice to see old friends grown up and in new situations. But it was also like a strange high school reunion. It’s a disorienting experience to be reunited with people who you’ve known since your childhood and who you walked the most formative experiences of your life with. Everyone is the same, but different—and not always for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first reading, this story seemed to do the one thing I hoped it would not. It changes the way I see the canonical series ending. And I don’t think the change honors the original series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I’m, disappointed in the play, even though there are plenty of great moments. Ms. Rowling did not write the script, but she does receive the lead credit on the story team. It’s unfortunate that she used her literary Time Turner to go back and revisit something so magnificent. Though I wish it was not true, this addition did not improve what was already perfected. If only the writer’s of this play would have heeded the lesson their protagonists learn about revising history.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You can never go home again.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">3 Reasons Why You Should Keep a Productivity Journal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/06/27/3-Reasons-Why-You-Should-Keep-a-Productivity-Journal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="3 Reasons Why You Should Keep a Productivity Journal" /><published>2016-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/06/27/3-Reasons-Why-You-Should-Keep-a-Productivity-Journal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/06/27/3-Reasons-Why-You-Should-Keep-a-Productivity-Journal.html">&lt;p&gt;Every day at 4pm, my phone dings with a reminder to write a journal entry. And (almost) every day I stop what I am doing and take a few moments to write about my day. It’s a simple act, but it is a crucial part of my productivity practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you read all of the productivity nerd blogs like I do, you probably have no clue what a “productivity journal” is. I didn’t either until a few years ago, but in that time this practice has become deeply important to my growth and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While more explanation is warranted, a productivity journal is simply a collection of daily entries summarizing your priorities, accomplishments, failures, and struggles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is keeping a productivity journal so important for me? Why do I think everyone who is interested in growth and productivity should keep one? It comes down to three benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-journal-maintains-our-focus-on-what-matters-most&quot;&gt;A journal maintains our focus on what matters most&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know about you, but I often lose sight of what matters over the course of the day. Every morning I start with a review that keeps me current with all my various inboxes and sets my priorities for the day. And very often by 4pm I have either finished everything I needed to, or got pulled off course by distractions. Either way, I tend to end my days with a cloudier view of my priorities than when I started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actor of journaling resets my focus. Sitting down to record what happened, detailing successes and failures, and thinking through what’s next clarifies the day. It puts the activities of the day into perspective. Did I meet my goals? Did I fail my team? Do I need to change something in response? What is one key thing I must do tomorrow? The act of thinking through these questions helps to settle my mind and organize my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-journal-is-raw-material-for-reflection&quot;&gt;A journal is raw material for reflection&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflection is a major part of my approach to productivity. In fact, it is the thing that keeps me on track. Leaving the much larger subject of reflection for other posts, the salient point is that regular, honest reflection on our decisions and outcomes is crucial to successfully implementing productive practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The journal serves two specific functions in my approach. First, by keeping a journal, each day I take time to reflect on the day. This has a self-ordering effect of sorting the days actions and decisions into a few camps. I can reflect on what was successful and what wasn’t. I also contemplate how I sinned or struggled to love others well. And finally I start to grapple with what the next day will bring. These areas all inform my understanding of the day. They are an immediate touch point for me on what matters most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, the permanent recording of these events and thoughts serve as grist for further reflection down the road. Reviewing a week, month, or even a year’s worth of journal entries reveals patterns of success and failure both. The raw data of each day’s thoughts can be used to construct a far more accurate view of my life and choices. It is the starting point for considering what changes need to be made so I can live a life that glorifies God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-journal-is-a-great-transition-out-of-your-work-day&quot;&gt;A journal is a great transition out of your work day&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final reason I find journalling to be so important is that it helps me begin to unwind my mind from the daily tasks, issues, and frustrations of work. It sums up the day—for good or for bad—in a way that allows me to put work away and switch modes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This frees me up to focus my thoughts on my wife and what she needs, or on personal projects that lie in wait at home. It helps me transition from one area of life to another cleanly. It sorts the mental debris of the day in an ordered way for the next day’s work. It’s cleans up the mental workbench, and shuts off the workshop lights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The importance of journalling does not lie in the journal itself, but in the act of recording and reflecting each day. A small break at the end of the day to reflect has made an huge difference for me, and it may do the same for you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Every day at 4pm, my phone dings with a reminder to write a journal entry. And (almost) every day I stop what I am doing and take a few moments to write about my day. It’s a simple act, but it is a crucial part of my productivity practice.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Productivity Practices Matter for All Christians</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/06/13/Why-Productivity-Practices-Matter-for-All-Christians.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Productivity Practices Matter for All Christians" /><published>2016-06-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-06-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/06/13/Why-Productivity-Practices-Matter-for-All-Christians</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/06/13/Why-Productivity-Practices-Matter-for-All-Christians.html">&lt;p&gt;Jesus was the most productive person ever. That might sound obvious to some, or trivial to others, but I believe that truth is incredibly important to believers living in the modern world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do I mean when I say that? What’s my point? It’s simple really:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jesus always did the right thing, with the right people, at the right time, and in the right way, always.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we learn to do the right things, with the right people, at the right time, and in the right way, we become &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; like Jesus. For the believer the end goal of improving our productivity is actually sanctification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are other results and purposes behind improving our productivity. I totally agree with Matt Perman when he asserts that our productivity is about doing all that we can, with all that we have, for the glory of God. Being more productive (in the sense that Jesus was productive), absolutely leads us to love our neighbors, families, churches, communities, and the world. It leads us to a greater impact for the kingdom of God. Being more productive is absolutely about glorifying God, &lt;em&gt;as is all of life&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, in the day-to-day mess—especially when it’s hard to be disciplined and organized—what drives me forward is this simple idea: becoming more productive means that I am becoming more like Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Jesus was the most productive person ever. That might sound obvious to some, or trivial to others, but I believe that truth is incredibly important to believers living in the modern world.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why I Switched to Jekyll from WordPress</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/05/07/why-i-switched-to-jekyll-from-wordpress.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why I Switched to Jekyll from WordPress" /><published>2016-05-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-05-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/05/07/why-i-switched-to-jekyll-from-wordpress</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/05/07/why-i-switched-to-jekyll-from-wordpress.html">&lt;p&gt;This post is the first post on the new version of this site. If you are a regular reader then I’m sure you noticed the much cleaner and more mobile-friendly design. But what you probably didn’t notice—unless you routinely scrutinize URLs—is that this is now a static site. I left WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, for most readers of this site this won’t matter at all. Load times will be much faster, but it wasn’t noticeably slow before. Other than that, moving from a dynamic, server-side site to a static, HTML site won’t make one bit of difference to you. But it does to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WordPress is not terrible. But it’s not &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt;, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I started blogging in 2003, I’ve used almost every major platform. Blogger, WordPress, Squarespace, and then WordPress again. I’ve never been happy with any of them, really. So when I started &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.brianlundin.com&quot;&gt;my tech blog last year&lt;/a&gt; I wanted something different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For that site I chose &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. Jekyll is a static site generator, not a blog platform, per se. Using text files written in &lt;a href=&quot;https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&quot;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Shopify/liquid/wiki&quot;&gt;Liquid templates&lt;/a&gt;, HTML, JavaScript, and CSS it generates my whole website in a few seconds. From there I host it on Amazon’s S3 for a few cents a month. Last month it cost me just under $.50 to host and serve the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I got it in place it worked perfectly. Pages loaded super fast, I could customize the site using the tools I’ve used for years as a web developer and not some janky themes or plugins. I was able to create a clean, readable, and responsive site quickly and host it cheaply.
After using Jekyll for just a few months I began work converting this site to Jekyll today. This post is the first on the new site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the decision was easy. I went with Jekyll for 5 reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I first went with WordPress to use some fancy, SEO-optimized themes. The theme(s) were not worth the money&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beyond those themes, all of the “features” of WordPress were not only unnecessary, they made it harder for me to create the kind of site I wanted. The platform is overgrown and cluttered with features that don’t add much discernible value&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I don’t need to post “on-the-go” from my phone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I do all my writing in Markdown, and WordPress did not offer an acceptable workflow for it. Yes, even with the fancy plugins and Markdown “integration”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finally, and most decisively, I had the technical skills to code my own site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This last reason is why most people will not be able to make the same choice I did. Even with &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulstamatiou.com/hosting-on-amazon-s3-with-cloudfront/&quot;&gt;great guides out there like the one I used&lt;/a&gt;, implementing a custom Jekyll site is still beyond the average blogger’s reach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I think static sites like this one are (or should be) the future for most independent writers on the web. Depending on your business model, there are very few downsides. If you need a membership site or other server-side features this would not be a good choice, but otherwise static sites have huge advantages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not making a living off this site, so I don’t have those needs. So with Jekyll I can run this blog cheaply, easily, and it fits right into my existing writing workflow. It really is perfect for me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This post is the first post on the new version of this site. If you are a regular reader then I’m sure you noticed the much cleaner and more mobile-friendly design. But what you probably didn’t notice—unless you routinely scrutinize URLs—is that this is now a static site. I left WordPress.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Colophon</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/05/06/Colophon.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Colophon" /><published>2016-05-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-05-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/05/06/Colophon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/05/06/Colophon.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colophon&lt;/strong&gt; \ˈkä-lə-fən, -ˌfän\
an inscription placed at the end of a book or manuscript usually with facts relative to its production&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The colophon is set for a comeback. With so many new digital publishing options, platforms and approaches, there is a natural opening and call for sites to share how they do what they do. In the spirit of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colophon_(publishing)&quot;&gt;the traditional colophon&lt;/a&gt;, I offer this summary of the tools behind this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Typography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://typekit.com/fonts/futura-pt&quot;&gt;Futura PT&lt;/a&gt;: headers, sans serif&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fontfont.com/fonts/tisa&quot;&gt;Tisa&lt;/a&gt;: body text, serif&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;: static blogging software&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://typekit.com&quot;&gt;Typekit.com&lt;/a&gt;: fonts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sublimetext.com/2&quot;&gt;Sublime Text 2&lt;/a&gt;: text editor (coding)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ulyssesapp.com&quot;&gt;Ulysses&lt;/a&gt;: text editor (markdown files and posts)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://marked2app.com&quot;&gt;Marked 2&lt;/a&gt;: markdown preview&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.photoshop.com/products/photoshop&quot;&gt;Photoshop CC&lt;/a&gt;: image and photo editing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aws.amazon.com/s3/&quot;&gt;Amazon S3&lt;/a&gt;: static site hosting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aws.amazon.com/cloudfront/&quot;&gt;Amazon CloudFront&lt;/a&gt;: global content distribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Colophon \ˈkä-lə-fən, -ˌfän\ an inscription placed at the end of a book or manuscript usually with facts relative to its production</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">‘Prayer’ by Tim Keller</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/06/23/Prayer-by-Tim-Keller.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="'Prayer' by Tim Keller" /><published>2015-06-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2015-06-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2015/06/23/Prayer-by-Tim-Keller</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2015/06/23/Prayer-by-Tim-Keller.html">&lt;p&gt;I read &lt;em&gt;Prayer&lt;/em&gt; by Tim Keller, and I immediately plan on reading it again. I use “read” loosely as it was an audiobook, and my next reading will be on paper. I love audiobooks, I’m not a hater. But in reading this book I realized that I cannot listen to nonfiction books that I want to retain. I remember bits and pieces from the book, to be discussed below, but honestly most of it slipped through my mind like sand through fingers. I enjoyed listening to the book, but I didn’t retain enough to meaningfully shape my understanding and practice of prayer. So, on that note it was a failed experience, but it’s not the work’s fault, just the medium’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did pick up a few things from the book that make it worthwhile. First, using Scripture readings as a basis for mediation as a transition into prayer. The REAP (Read, Examine, Apply, and Pray) that The Austin Stone recommends is useful, and actually works in a similar way to what Keller describes, but in my practice I have not actually meditated on Scripture, instead I just examine and apply through intellectual means. I want to start intentionally applying a meditation step into my routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, I really appreciated the thorough survey of the topic Keller offered, and how he centered on a few influential Protestants in our tradition to draw specifics from. It was a good choice and I helped me think through the practicals of prayer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have much else to say because of the audiobook issue. Lesson learned. I may write more the next time I read it. 😉&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I read Prayer by Tim Keller, and I immediately plan on reading it again. I use “read” loosely as it was an audiobook, and my next reading will be on paper. I love audiobooks, I’m not a hater. But in reading this book I realized that I cannot listen to nonfiction books that I want to retain. I remember bits and pieces from the book, to be discussed below, but honestly most of it slipped through my mind like sand through fingers. I enjoyed listening to the book, but I didn’t retain enough to meaningfully shape my understanding and practice of prayer. So, on that note it was a failed experience, but it’s not the work’s fault, just the medium’s.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">‘Writing A Novel with Ulysses’ by David Hewson</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/05/24/Writing-A-Novel-with-Ulysses-III-by-David-Hewson.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="'Writing A Novel with Ulysses' by David Hewson" /><published>2015-05-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2015-05-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2015/05/24/Writing-A-Novel-with-Ulysses-III-by-David-Hewson</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2015/05/24/Writing-A-Novel-with-Ulysses-III-by-David-Hewson.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been on a string of high-minded books lately, but now I’ve dove into a few books about writing itself, and the first one was novelist David Hewson’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1OhZqVj&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Writing A Novel with Ulysses III&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, it’s about as low-level as you can get, reading a book about how to write another book in a specific app. Whee!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was really useful. I’ve recently started using &lt;a href=&quot;http://ulyssesapp.com&quot;&gt;Ulysses&lt;/a&gt; for most of my writing for this blog, Story Team, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://storyteam.org&quot;&gt;Storyteam.org&lt;/a&gt;. I have the start of a novel project in Scrivener (which I like quite a bit), but the idea of having all my working in a single app and library was appealing. But from what I knew of Ulysses, I wasn’t sure I could really use it for a novel. Hence, this read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best review I can give of the book is this: it is short, thorough, and I’m now convinced I can write a novel quite well in it. And I am going to try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like writing in Markdown and the idea of a very basic writing app (NOT word processor as you know it) appeals to you, I would highly recommend both Ulysses and &lt;em&gt;Writing A Novel with Ulysses III&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’ve been on a string of high-minded books lately, but now I’ve dove into a few books about writing itself, and the first one was novelist David Hewson’s Writing A Novel with Ulysses III.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">‘How Dante Can Save Your Life’ by Rod Dreher</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/05/23/How-Dante-Can-Save-Your-Life-by-Rod-Dreher.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="'How Dante Can Save Your Life' by Rod Dreher" /><published>2015-05-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2015-05-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2015/05/23/How-Dante-Can-Save-Your-Life-by-Rod-Dreher</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2015/05/23/How-Dante-Can-Save-Your-Life-by-Rod-Dreher.html">&lt;p&gt;I was really skeptical about &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1T47LQL&quot;&gt;Rod Dreher’s new book &lt;em&gt;How Dante Can Save Your Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. When he started writing about it on his blog I wasn’t interested—at all. I started skipping posts about Dante. After being deeply affected by his two previous books I was not even going to read this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was wrong, and I’m glad I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to read it when he started talking about how it intersected with his life. As relayed in his last book, &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1OhZrbK&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Little Way of Ruthie Leming&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Rod struggled mightily with family issues of loyalty, trust and place. When I realized that this book would continue where the previous book left off, I decided to take a chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was wonderful. I honestly don’t remember why I doubted it would be. Rod used light literary criticism and memoir to spin a deeply emotional and personal tale of how God works on our hearts through art. This was right up my alley, and I was going to pass it by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a reader, you don’t have to know anything about Dante or his &lt;em&gt;Divine Comedy&lt;/em&gt; to read and appreciate this book. Rod’s careful treatment and plain-spoken approach make it an approachable experience for all readers. But in doing so he does not shy away from the complexities of the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a wonderfully fun read, I ripped through it in just a few days. If this sounds even slightly interesting to you I highly recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I was really skeptical about Rod Dreher’s new book How Dante Can Save Your Life. When he started writing about it on his blog I wasn’t interested—at all. I started skipping posts about Dante. After being deeply affected by his two previous books I was not even going to read this one.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">‘All the Pretty Horses’ by Cormac McCarthy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/04/20/All-the-Pretty-Horses-by-Cormac-McCarthy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="'All the Pretty Horses' by Cormac McCarthy" /><published>2015-04-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2015-04-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2015/04/20/All-the-Pretty-Horses-by-Cormac-McCarthy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2015/04/20/All-the-Pretty-Horses-by-Cormac-McCarthy.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;He’d never touched her and her hand was small and her waist so slight and she looked at him with great forthrightness and smiled and put her face against his shoulder. They turned under the lights. A long trumpet note guided the dancers on their separate and collective paths. Moths circled the paper lights aloft and the goathawks passed down the wires and flared and arced upward into the darkness again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my favorite paragraph in the whole book. It’s a beautiful paragraph that inspires and taunts me. In many ways McCarthy’s style runs so counter to my own, yet I cannot help but aspire to it. Of course, it’s a hopeless aspiration, because even if I was to achieve writing on this level, it would be my own and not his. But it’s an aspiration nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cormac McCarthy is an author who intimidates me. He does so more than any of the other authors I admire so much. More than Hugo, Hemingway, Lewis and Rowling, Cormac McCarthy’s work seems like a towering statue on the horizon, an unmovable stone giant lording over the barren waste before him. He is who he is, and his work stands above all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve often heard that &lt;em&gt;All the Pretty Horses&lt;/em&gt; is his most accessible work. I think that’s true, but I’m not sure that is where I would advise someone to start. It’s either this or &lt;em&gt;The Road&lt;/em&gt;, and depending on who the recommendation is for it’s probably a coin flip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our focus falls upon John Grady for this book. He’s the final heir to a long line of Texas ranchers, and he longs for a way of life that is long gone. He leaves for Mexico, looking for remnants of a world that has past, and maybe never was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his travels and travails we find the dying cries of the Old West. McCarthy writes in a manner that suits the land, economical in pace, beautiful in language, and honest about the ugliness of the world John Grady found. It’s a powerful story of love and honor, and one that feels all to real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book in particular moved me in a way that I miss. It reminded me of the joy of reading a great writer at the height of his mastery. Like the best works, it makes me want to write. It drives me to create, even if I can never reach the bar it sets.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">He’d never touched her and her hand was small and her waist so slight and she looked at him with great forthrightness and smiled and put her face against his shoulder. They turned under the lights. A long trumpet note guided the dancers on their separate and collective paths. Moths circled the paper lights aloft and the goathawks passed down the wires and flared and arced upward into the darkness again.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Evolution of Podcasting: Inquisitive, The Record &amp;amp; Welcome to Macintosh</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/03/09/The-Evolution-of-Podcasting-Inquisitive-The-Record-Welcome-to-Macintosh.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Evolution of Podcasting: Inquisitive, The Record &amp; Welcome to Macintosh" /><published>2015-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2015-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2015/03/09/The-Evolution-of-Podcasting-Inquisitive-The-Record-Welcome-to-Macintosh</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2015/03/09/The-Evolution-of-Podcasting-Inquisitive-The-Record-Welcome-to-Macintosh.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://serialpodcast.org&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Serial&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; blew up the podcasting world last fall. For many, many people &lt;em&gt;Serial&lt;/em&gt; was their first impression of podcasting. For many others, myself included, it was a very visible step forward in a medium that has been full of less visible, but even more important, steps forward for the last 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serial is a very different show than the one that formed my first impression of podcasting, Adam Curry’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daily_Source_Code&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Daily Source Code&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in 2005. The public radio polish and production quality is miles ahead of those original podcasts, and of many popular shows today. Many old guard podcast folks from the tech world scoffed at &lt;em&gt;Serial&lt;/em&gt; as nothing new, just an evolution of one of the most popular radio shows-turned-podcasts in the world, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thisamericanlife.org&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This American Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They might be right, but I don’t care if that’s true. In the more traditional world of tech podcasting there a few new shows who are taking their cue from public radio-style storytelling podcasts. Because these are shows without public radio budgets and they are still doing top-notch work, they are the ones really driving the medium forward. Where Serial may have been the general public’s introduction to podcasting, shows like &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.relay.fm/inquisitive&quot;&gt;Inquisitive&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://therecord.co&quot;&gt;The Record&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/welcome-to-macintosh/id970061020?mt=2&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome to Macintosh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are podcasting’s introduction to storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure that there are other shows doing similar work, but these are shows that made their appearance in my corner of the internet, in this case the Apple fanboy section. &lt;em&gt;Inquisitive&lt;/em&gt; rebooted the show in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.relay.fm/inquisitive/27&quot;&gt;episode #27: Behind the App #1&lt;/a&gt;. The show evolved from its one-on-one interview style to a story-driven format featuring multiple guests and telling one long story over the course of many episodes. By documenting the history of the iTunes App Store and the app industry up to the current moment, Myke Hurley is creating a valuable historical record while also weaving a compelling narrative. Along with &lt;em&gt;Welcome to Macintosh&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/welcome-to-macintosh/id970061020?mt=2#&quot;&gt;currently on episode #1&lt;/a&gt;) and last year’s &lt;em&gt;The Record&lt;/em&gt; from Brent Simmons and Chris Parrish will document one of the most interesting aspects of the (current) world’s most valuable company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hope is that more and more podcast producers, and people who aren’t making shows yet, are inspired by this growing number of shows that tell compelling stories in long form. Storytelling is a powerful medium. Narrative stories connect with people in ways that nothing else can. I hope that this is the beginning of a new renaissance in storytelling, and podcasts lead the way. The podcasting world and all of us will be better off for it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Serial blew up the podcasting world last fall. For many, many people Serial was their first impression of podcasting. For many others, myself included, it was a very visible step forward in a medium that has been full of less visible, but even more important, steps forward for the last 10 years.</summary></entry></feed>